Saki, why are you
so spaced-out?
I was just thinking about something.
ちょっと考えごとしてただけ
当ててみようか
良のことでしょ？
Let me guess.
Is it about Ryou?
良？
隠さなくてもいいって
Ryou?
No need to hide it.
You worried about whether he’ll pick you, right?
選んでくれるかどうか
心配なんでしょう？
えっ？
大丈夫
Don’t worry.
I know he will.
良は 絶対 早季のこと好きだから
He likes you, you know?
良は２班じゃない
どうして 私を選ぶの？
Isn’t Ryou in Group Two?
Why would he pick me?
Come on, is your memory going?
何 言ってるのよ 今さら
そんなの最初だけでしょ？
That was ages ago!
１班に入ってから ずっと
We’ve been a team ever since he joined Group One!
私たちと 一緒に
行動してたじゃない
２班には６人いたのに
That happened because Group Two used to have six members, while Group One only had four.
１班は 最初から
４人しかいなかったからだ
Why weren’t there enough members to begin with?
そもそも
なぜ人数が少なかったんだろうか
早季？
Saki?
Are you okay?
どうしたの？ ちょっと変よ
You seem out of it.
Stop that…
ああ… もう やめてよ
ほ～ら もう元気になった
See? Now you feel better.
I wasn’t asking you to do that.
別に こんなことしてほしかった
わけじゃない
してほしい人は別にいるもんね
I think I know whom you would’ve preferred.
That’s totally not what I was thinking!
全然 思ってないってば！
いつも仲がいいね
You two get along so well.
Hey there, Ryou.
あ～ら 良 私たち
愛し合ってるのよ やける？
We’re living out our love here.
Jealous?
正直 言うと ちょっとね
Yeah, a little, to be honest.
どっちに？
Of whom?
両方かな
Both of you, I guess.
You liar.
ウソつき
Do you have a minute, Saki?
早季 ちょっと話をしない？
ふ～ん 邪魔者は消えるから
お幸せにね
I’ll get out of your way.
Enjoy!
守がずっと見ていたよ
Mamoru was watching the whole time.
事前投票で 君が
圧倒的な１位だと分かったから
When you came in first in the preliminary poll
by a wide margin, it really shook his confidence.
気が気じゃないみたいだね
ふふん もてすぎるのも罪なものね
Being too popular just isn’t good, is it?
ここは騒がしいから
外へ行かないか？
Let’s go somewhere more quiet.
いいけど
All right.
この冬 生徒たちは
全員２人１組の当番委員に
That winter, all students were divided into groups of two to serve on duty.
振り分けられることになっていた
建前の上では日直や様々な行事の
On the surface this merely encompassed day-to-day duties and various ceremonial preparations.
準備作業を行う
役割に過ぎなかったが
男女お互いの指名で成り立つので
However, a pair would only form if a boy and girl chose each other, so it was none other than a formal declaration of love.
実際には愛を告白するための
公式行事に他ならなかった
Episode Eleven
Distant
Thunder
in Winter
Wait.
待って そっちは行きたくない
I don’t want to go over there.
どうして？
Why?
I… What do you want to do over there?
それは…
そっちに行ってどうするの？
Nobody will disturb us here.
こっちは誰も来ないから
ほら この先は
中庭への入口しかないから
It just leads to the inner yard.
中庭…
The inner yard…
Don’t you want to go outside instead?
それより外に出ない？
The weather’s so nice.
天気がいいから気持ちいいわ
そう？ 分かった
All right. Let’s do that.
I’m going to nominate you as my duty pair partner.
当番委員のことなんだけど
僕は早季を指名するからね
ありがとう
Thanks.
That’s all?
それだけ？
それだけって？
What do you mean?
早季はどうなの？
Who will you nominate?
I…
私は…
ごめんなさい まだ決めてないの
I’m sorry.
I haven’t decided yet.
あっ… 他に誰かいるの？
Is there someone else?
う～ん… 特に いないけど…
Not really, but…
良は どうして私なの？
Why would you nominate me, Ryou?
Isn’t that obvious?
そんなの決まってるじゃないか
今まで ずっと早季を見てきて
I’ve been watching you all this time. For me, you’re the only one.
君しかいないって思ったからさ
All this time?
ずっとって？
Since when?
いつから
そう思うようになったの？
I don’t really remember.
いつからだろう？
そういうのって
You can’t really put your finger on something like that, right?
はっきり いつからって
決められないだろう？
でも 強いて言えば
But if I had to decide, I’d say since we spent time together during summer camp.
夏季キャンプに
一緒に行ってからかな
何が いちばん思い出に残ってる？
What’s your favorite memory?
All of it!
そりゃあ 全部だよ
一緒にカヌーをこいだり…
When we were rowing together…
ほら 君が景色に見とれて
川に落ちそうになって
Remember? You were so busy looking at the scenery you almost fell into the river.
僕が とっさに手をつかんで
止めたことがあったじゃないか
I quickly took your hand and kept you in the boat.
そんなこと あったっけ？
Did that really happen?
楽しかったよ
It was a lot of fun.
覚の目を見たとき ゾクリとした
そこにあったのは
The look in Satoru’s eyes gave me goosebumps.
What I saw there could only be described as pure confusion.
純粋な不可解さとでも
形容すべきだろうか
人が全く理解できない存在を
見るときの目だった
They were the eyes of someone who had seen something completely irreconcilable with common sense.
Have you forgotten about me already?
僕のことは
もう忘れてしまったの？
I’m sorry.
ごめんなさい
どうしても思い出せないの
I just can’t remember, even if I try.
そうか…
それなら しかたがないね
I see.
That’s okay, then.
Where are you?
どこにいるの？ 顔を見せて
Let me see your face.
I have no face.
僕には顔がないんだ
You should know well what I look like, though.
でも 僕の顔なら
君はよく知ってるはずだよ
I don’t know.
分からない 思い出せないの
I can’t remember.
It’s not your fault.
それは君のせいじゃない
誰かが僕を葬った後で
Someone chiseled off the lettering on the gravestone they put above me.
墓標の文字を
削り取ったからなんだよ
Someone?
誰かって？
どうして そんなことするの？
Why would they do that?
Look there.
あっちを見てごらん
みんな そうなんだ
We are all the same.
A mirror?
鏡？
Don’t be afraid.
大丈夫だよ 怖くなんかないから
それは君のお墓じゃないんだよ
There’s no danger.
It’s not your own gravestone.
じゃあ 誰の？
Then whose is it?
Take a good look at it.
いいから よく見てごらん
You will understand then.
そうすれば分かるから
Yoshimi
Duty Pair Vote
それでね… あっ
And then—
やあ きょうはよろしく
Hey. Big day today.
I’ve got something to talk about.
ちょっと話があるんだけど
Sure.
いいよ どこかへ行く？
Want to go somewhere?
Anywhere works.
どこでも すぐに すむ話だから
It won’t take long.
あなたに
いくつか聞きたいことがあるの
There are a few things I want to ask you.
Sure.
いいよ 何でも聞いてみて
Ask away.
２人でナイトカヌーをしてた時の
ことなんだけど
When we were in the canoe together, at night…
あっ… 何だ またその話か
Oh… That again…
あなたは私に ナイトカヌーには
鉄則があるって教えてくれたわ
You taught me something fundamental about night rowing.
Do you remember what it was?
何だったか覚えてる？
ああ…
しばらく たき火の方を
見ちゃだめだよ
Don’t look at the fire.
Why?
どうして？
It’s a basic tenet of night rowing.
ナイトカヌーの鉄則は
You have to let your eyes get accustomed to the darkness.
乗り込む前に しっかり
目を慣らしておくことなんだ
そうでないと しばらくは
何も見えないからね
Otherwise you won’t be able to see anything for a while.
そんな前のこと
よく覚えてないな…
That’s so long ago.
I don’t really remember.
何だろう 岩にぶつからないように
気をつけることだったかな？
What was it?
Was it about steering clear of the rocks?
That’s all right.
いいわ じゃあ もっと最近の話よ
Let’s talk about something more recent, then.
どうして 覚と別れたの？
Why did you break up with Satoru?
そんなことは…
I… Does that really matter anymore?
もう どうでもいいじゃないか
But you two used to be so close.
あんなに仲がよかったのに？
そうだったかな…
I guess…
じゃあ 最後の質問
Okay, last question.
また夏季キャンプのことに
戻るけど
It’s about summer camp again.
いいよ もう何でも
All right. That’s fine.
It’s about Rijin…
離塵師のこと
どうして死んだか覚えてる？
Do you remember how he died?
｢リジンシ｣って何？
死んだ？ それ 何の話？
Who’s Rijin?
He died? What are you talking about?
Never mind.
もういいわ やっぱり
あなたじゃなかったのね
It really wasn’t you, I guess.
どういうこと？
What do you mean?
私 当番委員の紙に
あなたの名前は書かないわ
I won’t put your name down for the duty pair nomination.
そんな… どうして？
But… Why?
I’m really sorry.
本当にごめんなさい
I thought it would be good manners to tell you first.
でも 先に断っておくのが
礼儀だと思うから
アイツの名前を書くのか？
Are you going to choose him?
書くわけないじゃん
No way I would.
えっ… 何でだよ？
Why?
I have a question for you too.
覚こそ
どうして良を好きになったの？
Why did you like Ryou?
Why… Uh…
へっ？ どうしてって…
何でだろう 今になってみると…
I wonder…
I can’t seem to remember anymore.
よく分からないな
やっぱりね
I know what you mean.
He’s a nice guy.
悪いコじゃないんだけど
ミスキャストだったんだ
He’s just not fit for the role.
I’m certain it wasn’t him.
絶対 彼じゃなかったわ
私たち２人が好きになった人は
He’s not the one we both fell in love with.
Duty Pair Vote
どういうこと？
良じゃなかったって
What do you mean, “it wasn’t Ryou”?
だから 違うのよ 私たちは
５人で夏季キャンプに行ったけど
Because it wasn’t him!
There were five of us during summer camp, but he wasn’t among us!
入ってなかったんだって
そんな訳ないわ 覚えてるもの
That’s ridiculous.
I remember him!
いちばん最初に カヤノスヅクリの
巣を見つけたのだって
He was the one who found the haythatcher’s nest first.
良だったじゃない
あれは 良なんかじゃなかったのよ
That wasn’t Ryou.
じゃあ 誰？
Then who was it?
分かんない
どうしても名前が出てこないの
I don’t know.
The name just won’t come to me.
Describe him.
どんなコ？ 顔は？
What did he look like?
顔も思い出せない
I can’t remember that either.
あのねえ そんなバカな話
信じられるわけないでしょう？
Come on, do you really expect me to believe that?
本当に
どうかしちゃったんじゃないの？
Aren’t you just a little under the weather?
There’s a part of me that feels the same, though.
でも
俺も思い当たる部分があるんだ
俺 アイツとつきあってたっていう
記憶はあるんだけど…
I have memories of going out with that boy,
どう考えても
良じゃなかったと思うんだよ
but I simply can’t imagine him being Ryou.
だってアイツ 好みじゃないんだ
He’s… not my type.
Well, I know you’ve got the hots for the cute and younger-looking ones.
そりゃあ 覚の好みは かわいい
美少年だって知ってるけど
怜みたいなね
Like Rei, right?
But well, sometimes you don’t know what you’re doing.
でも まあ 魔が差したってことも
あるんじゃない？
押しの 一手でこられて ついとか
Maybe he was just persistent enough.
それも違うんだよ
I don’t think so.
俺の方から しつこいくらいに
言い寄ってたんだ
I was the one who had to persuade him.
とにかく 俺らが
記憶を操作されてんのは
Anyway, I’m pretty sure our memories have been tinkered with.
間違いないと思う
つじつまが合わないことがある
The details just don’t add up.
どんな？
Such as?
Ryou’s… No, that’s too confusing. Let’s call him “X”.
良の… 紛らわしいから
｢Ｘ｣にするよ
ちっちゃい頃に 俺 何度か
Ｘんちに行った記憶があるんだ
I remember playing a lot at X’s place when I was little.
でも そこは良の家とは違ってた
But Ryou’s house looks different.
ほら 良んちって
見晴の郷にあるだろ？
Ryou lives in the village of Outlook, right?
丘の上で かなり開けた場所じゃん
でも Ｘんちは
It’s up on a hill and fairly open.
But X’s house was…
はっ！ 森の中だったわ
In the middle of a forest!
そう ずっと北の方で 一軒だけ
ぽつんとある大きな家だった
Yeah. It was off to the north. A big, isolated house.
言われてみれば…
I remember that too, now that you mention it.
私も覚えてるわ
I’ve never been to Ryou’s or X’s place,
僕は 良もＸの家にも
行ったことはないけど
北の方で森っていうと どこかな？
but where would this forest to the north be?
Hey, tell me the names of all the seven villages.
ねえ ７つの郷 全部 言ってみて
え？ 何だよ 今さら
Huh? Are you serious?
いいから言ってみてよ
Just do it!
Um, Oakgrove, Withertree, Whitesand, Gold, Waterwheel, Outlook, and Hayring, wasn’t it?
だから 櫟林 朽木 白砂 黄金
水車 見晴 あと茅輪だろ？
森っていったら櫟林？
でも 北だったら朽木かしら
A forest would mean Oakgrove?
But Withertree is to the north.
でも あっちに
そんな大きな家は…
The buildings there are all fairly small, though.
確かに あんまりイメージないな
あっこまで行くと
Yeah, it’s hard to imagine it being there.
Most of that area seems to be outside the Holy Barrier.
ほとんど
八丁標の外って感じだよな
Let’s go!
行ってみようよ
どこへ？
Where to?
朽木よ 決まってるじゃない
To Withertree, of course!
But today’s the first day for the duty pairs!
当番委員のペアが
決まった日なのよ？
みんな お祝いしてるのに
何が悲しくて
Everyone’s celebrating!
Why do we have to go to some
abandoned village and dwell on the past?
そんな さびれ果てたとこへ
行かなきゃならないの？
Any idea where the people here went?
ここにいた人たちって
どこに行ったんだろう？
何か 天災か
事故みたいなことがあって
Wasn’t there a disaster of some sort and they had to resettle in the other villages?
他の郷に
引っ越したんじゃなかったっけ？
Ｘの家は ずっと北のはずよね
X’s house was even further north, wasn’t it?
行きましょ
Let’s go.
What on Earth happened here?
何が起きたら
こんなふうになるんだ？
すごい呪力を持ってる人が
ねじ曲げたんじゃない？
It must’ve been someone with really powerful Cantus.
何のためだよ？
Why, though?
私に分かるわけないじゃない
I don’t know any more than you do.
朽木の郷って こんなに狭いの？
Was Withertree this small?
いや 違うな この縄は
まだ作られて間もないんじゃ…
No, it wasn’t.
This rope here is brand-new too.
A lake?
こんなとこに…
I don’t remember this at all.
全然 知らなかったわ…
There can’t be any buildings further out.
この先に
家なんてありそうもないね
やっぱり 気のせいだったんだよ
We must be misremembering.
Ｘなんていないんだって
X doesn’t exist.
じゃあ どうして？
Then how do you explain this?
私も 早季や覚の言ってること
ちょっとだけ感じてた
I have a feeling I know what Saki and Satoru meant.
I feel like maybe, just maybe,
the boy we knew wasn’t Ryou.
私が知っていたのは
もしかしたら 良じゃなくて
別の男の子だったんじゃ
ないかって
錯覚だよ ほら 今くらいって
急激に大人になるから
It’s just a trick of the mind.
We grow fast these days, but not only taller.
背が伸びるだけじゃなくて
顔の感じとか
Our looks and personalities change as well.
性格まで どんどん
変わっていくじゃない？
ねえ もう１人いなかった？
えっ？
Hey, didn’t we have another friend?
Huh?
うちの班だけ４人っていうのは
やっぱり あり得ないと思う
It really is strange that only our team had four people.
だから
良が来る前にはＸがいたはずよ
X must have been in it before Ryou joined.
But we’re still missing another person.
でも それでも
１人少ないでしょ？
My memory is really fuzzy.
よく思い出せないんだけど
もう１人いたんじゃない？
But wasn’t there someone else?
There was. I remember.
いたよ 俺は覚えてる
少なくともＸのときみたく
Just like with X, some of my memories of that person remain.
記憶が完全に抹消されてるって
ことはないみたいだな
でも なんで
誰も話題にしないのかな？
But why doesn’t anyone talk about them?
Stop it!
ねえ やめようよ！
絶対 よくないって
This isn’t right!
We shouldn’t poke our noses into this!
そんなこと詮索するのは
そんな話ばっかりしてたら…
If we keep talking about this, we’ll…
してたら 何？
What will happen?
私たちも
処分されてしまうっていうの？
Are they going to dispose of us too?
Saki, is it just me or did we talk about that during summer camp too?
早季 確か そんな話
夏季キャンプでもしてなかった？
We did. I think we did.
した… したと思う
何を話したかは思い出せないけど
I don’t remember anything specific, though.
思い出そうとすると
頭の中で邪魔が入るんだ
I hit a wall or something when I pursue that train of thought.
でも 言ってたみたいだ
たき火のそばで
But I’m sure we talked about it.
Around a campfire.
そのとき 俺の意見に
賛成してくれたのはＸだった
X agreed with what I said then.
Stop, goddamn it!
やめろよ！ もう聞きたくない
I don’t want to hear any more!
We shouldn’t be talking about any of this!
そんな話
絶対にしたらだめなんだよ！
倫理規定違反だって！
We’re violating the Code of Ethics!
分かった 大丈夫よ
All right!
Calm down.
Let’s drop the issue, okay?
この話は もうやめましょう
いいわね
Please.
What do you think?
どう思う？
うん
かなり下手くそに見えるけど
Yoshimi
It looks badly made, but I think that’s because the creator was a beginner at Cantus.
このタッチは 初心者が
呪力で作ったものだと思う
So you’re saying that your older sister Yoshimi was uh…
吉美姉さん？
その人が学校に その…
処分されたっていうのは
…disposed of by the school?
Aren’t you jumping to conclusions now?
ちょっと
飛躍しすぎなんじゃない？
事故や病気で亡くなったんなら
隠す必要はないでしょ？
They wouldn’t have had to hide it
if she died from a sickness or an accident.
何か
つらすぎる思い出だったりしたら
What if they wanted to protect you from having sad memories?
でも この文字 見てよ
下手すぎると思わない？
Look at the characters!
Aren’t they just too clumsy?
姉は きちんと呪力を使えて
なかったんじゃないかと思うの
I think my sister couldn’t use her Cantus well.
それも やっぱり臆測でしかないよ
But that’s just speculation as well.
よく見ると 下手っていうのとは
ちょっと違うんじゃないかな
Now that I look at it carefully,
I’m no longer so sure it’s badly done.
早季 あなたの気持ちは
よく分かるわ
Saki, I really understand how you feel.
でも 頼むから
これ以上 騒ぎ立てたりしないで
But…
Please, don’t stir up any more trouble.
騒ぎ立てる？ 私は ただ
真実が知りたいだけなのよ
Stirring up trouble?!
I just want to know the truth!
姉のことだけじゃない
It’s not just my sister!
ウチの班にいた
女の子のことだって
We used to have another girl in our group too.
何よりも 私たちの友達のことを
And most importantly, we used to have another friend.
分かってる 私だって つらいわ
I know.
It’s not easy for me either.
I want to do something about it too.
何とかしたいっていう気持ちは
早季と 一緒よ
But I’m more worried about the friends who are alive right now.
だけど 私は
今 生きてる友達の方が心配なの
私のことだったら心配いらないわ
You don’t have to worry about me.
I’m not worried about you.
早季のことは心配してない
あなたは強いもの
You’re strong.
Strong? Me?
強い？ 私が？
Yes.
ええ あなたは
今 誰よりも深く傷ついてるわ
This is harder on you than anyone else.
でも 早季は それに耐えてる
But you’re enduring it.
普通だったら耐えられないほどの
悲しみだと思うのに
I think most people couldn’t bear that pain.
How could you?
ひどい…
私を 一体 何だと思ってるの？
What exactly do you take me for?
誤解しないで
Don’t misunderstand me.
あなたが冷たい人間だって
言ってるんじゃないのよ
I’m not saying that you’re heartless.
それどころか
早季は 人一倍感じやすいわ
On the contrary, you’re more sensitive than most.
だけど あなたは その悲しみや
苦しみを背負っていける人なのよ
But you’re able to shoulder that pain and sadness and live on.
私たちは みんな
あなたほど強くない
We aren’t all as strong as you are.
私なんか いつも
偉そうにしてるけどね
I’m always the first to give an opinion and be cheeky,
いざとなると
すぐに逃げ出したくなっちゃう
but during trouble I’m also the first to run away.
だけど 私や覚より
もっと 弱い人もいるのよ
But there’s someone who’s even weaker than Satoru or me.
もしかして 守のこと？
You mean Mamoru?
ええ 守は
すごく優しくて繊細なの
Yes.
He’s a kind and fragile spirit.
心から信じていた人に
裏切られたりしたら
He wouldn’t be able to cope with betrayal from someone he trusted.
もう立ち直れないわ
人だけじゃない
信じていた世界にも
And it’s not just about people.
He needs to be able to trust the world too.
I think there are probably many things in this world we are better off not knowing.
世の中には
知らない方がいいことって
たぶん いっぱいあるんだと思う
真実が いちばん残酷なことだって
あるでしょう？
Sometimes the truth is cruelest of all.
それに耐えられる
人ばっかりじゃないのよ
Not everyone can bear it.
これ以上 恐ろしい真実を
突きつけられたりしたら
I’m certain Mamoru would lose it if you
dug up more of these frightening truths.
守は きっと壊れちゃう
Okay.
分かった
本当？
Really?
I promise Mamoru will never hear another word of it.
約束する 守には
もう 聞かせないようにするから
だけど 私は 本当のことが
分かるまで絶対に諦めない
But I won’t give up until I know the truth.
だって そうじゃないと
If I don’t, he would haunt me forever.
あんまり かわいそう過ぎる
Do you have a minute?
あなたたち ちょっといいかしら？
渡辺早季さんですね？
You’re Watanabe Saki-san, right?
And Akizuki Maria-san and Asahina Satoru-kun?
それから 秋月 真理亜さんと
朝比奈 覚くん？
はい…
Can we help you?
いや
そんなに緊張しないでいいですよ
You don’t have to be so nervous.
We just want to talk to you.
ちょっと お話を
聞かせてもらいたいだけですから
あの… 教育委員会の方ですか？
Um, are you from the Board of Education?
いいえ 私たちは
あなたの おばあさまの下で
No, we’re working under your grandmother.
働いている者です
Really?
えっ？ そうなんですか？
朝日奈くんの おばあさまは
朝日奈 富子さまです
Asahina-kun’s grandmother is Asahina Tomiko-sama.
倫理委員会の
議長をなさってるんですよ
She’s the head of the Ethics Committee.
Please wait here. It won’t be long.
しばらく
ここで待っていてくださいね
ねえ これどういうこと？
What’s going on here?
おばあさんが議長だなんて
一度も聞いたことないわよ？
You never told us your grandma
was the head of the committee!
まさか 私たちのこと
You weren’t spying on us, right?
逐一 報告してたわけじゃ
ないでしょうね？
Slow down! I never knew either!
ちょっと待ってくれ
俺も知らなかったんだ
You didn’t know what?
知らなかったって 何を？
That my grandmother—I mean, that Asahina
Tomiko-san is the head of the Ethics Committee!
だから おばあさんっていうか
朝日奈 富子さんが
倫理委員会の
議長をしてたってことだよ
そんな ウソよ
You’ve got to be kidding me.
There’s no way that’s true.
ありえないでしょう？ 孫なのに
You’re her grandson!
Hear me out!
話を聞いてくれよ 大体
倫理委員会の議長が誰かなんて
Neither of you knew who the head was either!
お前らだって
知らなかったんだろ？
そりゃあ そうだけど
Yeah, but…
他の役職と違って
倫理委員は 全員非公開なんだよ
Unlike with other jobs, the members of the Ethics Committee aren’t public knowledge.
委員本人も
自分が委員だなんて認めないし
The members keep their own identities secret as well.
なんとなく 分かるんじゃないの？
Wouldn’t you have a gut feeling, though?
だって あなたの
おばあさんなんでしょう？
She’s your grandmother!
Excuse me!
失礼します
ああ…
I’m sorry we kept you waiting.
ごめんなさいね お待たせして
１人ずつ お話を聞きたいので
順番に来てくれるかしら？
We’d like to talk to you in turn, so would you please follow me one by one?
議長に報告したら
あなただけは お話を
When I notified the head of the committee,
she said she specifically wanted to talk to you.
じかに聞きたいということなのね
だから 今から
議長の執務室へ行きます
We’re going to her office now.
え… 覚の…
朝日奈 富子さんですか？
You mean Satoru’s—uh, Asahina Tomiko-san?
ええ とっても気さくで
優しい方ですからね
Yes. She’s kind and friendly.
緊張しなくていいわよ
No need to be nervous.
Nakisou na aoringo kakaeteru mune no oku
泣きそうな青リンゴ  抱えてる胸の奥
In my chest, I carry a green apple that wets my eyes
Korogatte tsuyogatte
転がって  強がって
I fall over yet pretend to be strong
Kyuukutsu na sora niramu
窮屈な空睨む
I glower at the sky and it seems to suffocate me
Unmei ni juujun ni
運命に従順に
Do I look like I'd wait quietly
Jukusu no wo matsu mon ka
熟すのを待つもんか
For destiny to ripen it?
Sen no kaze
千の風
The winds
Agaite sakende
あがいて  叫んで
I struggle and scream
Fuke fuke
吹け吹け
Blow and blow
Watashi wa shabondama
わたしはしゃぼん玉
I'm a soap bubble
Soredemo shinjiteru
それでも信じてる
And still I have faith
Yokisenu arashi ni
予期せぬ  嵐に
In a sudden storm
Joushou shite kakou shite
上昇して  下降して
I rise and fall
Aragau shabondama
あらがうしゃぼん玉
I fight, soap bubble that I am
Soredemo ikiteku
それでも生きてく
And still I live on
Hajikeru shunkan niji hanate
弾ける瞬間  虹、放て
I make a rainbow when I burst
失礼します
May we come in?
Come in.
どうぞ
あっ…
FROM
THE
NEW
WORLD
There are only two things in this world we need to be truly afraid of.
私たちにとって
ホントに恐ろしい存在が
この世で ２つしかないでしょ？
それ もしかして 最初から全部
仕組まれてたことなんですか？
Was it all part of your plan?
I saw it with my very own eyes.
私は この目で見たわ
それが
あなたしかできない仕事だからよ
It’s a task only you can accomplish.